Beveridge Collection of Unemployment, Volumes 1-20 on Microfilm 6130 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Beveridge Collection of Unemployment, Volumes 1-20 on Microfilm
1834- 1986
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
British Library of Political Economic Science (BLPES)
6130 mf
1.33 cubic feet
12 microfilm reels
Records, microfilm.
3900442
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 26, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 23, 2016
Scope and Contents
Central and local government reports, pamphlets and papers of the London Central (Unemployed) Body for London relating to the causes and incidence of unemployment in the United Kingdom and its cure including labour exchanges, benefits and relief. The collection is particularly rich in London material.
v. 1.Reports, 1886-1909, (reel 1) -- v. 2.Unemployment: Liverpool. etc., 1894-1908, (reel 2) -- v. 3.Unemployment: Oxford. etc., 1897-1909, (reel 2) -- v. 4.Unemployment, etc., 1890-1914, (reel 3) -- v. 5.Unemployed, Poor Law, etc., 1893- 1905, (reel 4) -- v. 6.Provincial Distress Committees, 1905 Oct.-1909, (reel 5) -- v. 7.London Unemployed, 1906-1907, (reel 6) -- v. 8.London Unemployed, 1903-1906, (reel 6) -- v. 9.London Unemployed, 1903-1908, (reel 7)
v. 10.Vagrancy and Labour Colonies, 1903-1906, (reel 7) -- v. 11.London: Central (Unemployed) Body for London, Minutes, 1905-1906, (reel 8) -- v. 12.London: Central (Unemployed) Body of London, Minutes, 1906-1907, (reel 8) -- v. 13.London: Central (Unemployed) Body for London, Minutes, 1907-1908, (reel 9) -- v. 14.Unemployed, Labour Exchanges, etc., 1887-1914, (reel 9) -- v. 15.Unemployment, 1893-1895, (reel 10) -- v. 16.Unemployed, Metropolitan Employment Exchanges, 1906-1910, (reel 11) -- v. 17.United Kingdom, Labour Dept., Board of Trade, 1908, (reel 11) -- v. 18.Central (Unemployed) Body for London, Reports, 1907-1914, (reel 11) -- v. 19.London, Central (Unemployed) Body for London, Minutes, 1908-1910, (reel 12) -- v. 20.Central (Unemployed) Body for London, Proceedings, 1914-1915, (reel 12)
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Unemployment -- Great Britain.; Social security -- Great Britain.
3900442
- Reports, 1886-1909: V.1. (Reel 1)
  - V.1-1. Charity Organization Society: Special Committees., 1886; 1 (Reel 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Report on the best means of dealing with exceptional distress, 1886.
  - V.1-2. Charity Organization Society, 1903; 2 (Reel 1)
    Suggestions for meeting distress due to want of employment, 1903.
  - V.1-3. Charity Organization Society: Occasional Paper, 1896; 3 (Reel 1)
    No. 53: Winter Distress, 1896.
  - V.1-4. Charity Organization Society: Occasional Paper, 1892; 4 (Reel 1)
    No. 29: Municipal workshops, 1892.
  - V.1-5. Charity Organization Society: Occasional Paper, 1892; 5 (Reel 1)
    No. 30: The Unemployed: 1892.
  - V.1-6. Charity Organization Society: Occasional Paper, 1892; 6 (Reel 1)
  - V.1-7. Charity Organization Society: Occasional Paper, 1889; 7 (Reel 1)
    No. 11: Suggestions and suggested rules for dealing with exceptional distress by local committees: 1889.
  - V.1-8. Charity Organization Society: Special Committee, 1891; 8 (Reel 1)
    Report on the homeless poor of London: 1891.
  - V.1-9. Charity Organization Society: Special Committee on Unskilled Labour., 1908; 9 (Reel 1)
    Report and minutes of evidence: 1908.
  - V.1-10. United Kingdom: Statutory Rules and Orders, 1905; 10 (Reel 1)
    No. 1034: Unemployed workmen. The Organisation (Unemployed Workmen) Establishment Order, 1905.
  - V.1-11. United Kingdom: Statutory Rules and Orders, 1905; 11 (Reel 1)
    No. 1034. Circular - London - Councils and guardians: Unemployed Workmen Act, 1905.
  - V.1-12. United Kingdom: Statutory Rules and Orders, 1905; 12 (Reel 1)
    No. 1035. Unemployed workmen: the Urban Distress Committees (Unemployed Workmen) Order, 1905.
  - V.1-13. United Kingdom: Statutory Rules and Orders, 1905; 13 (Reel 1)
    No. 1035. Circular - Councils and Guardians in populous boroughs and urban districts. Unemployed Workmen Act, 1905.
  - V.1-14. United Kingdom: Statutory Rules and Orders, 1905; 14 (Reel 1)
    No. 1071. Unemployed workmen. The Regulations (Organisation for Unemployed), 1905.
  - V.1-15. United Kingdom: Statutory Rules and Orders, 1905; 15 (Reel 1)
    No. 1071. Circular - London, City and Metropolitan Boroughs. Unemployed Workmen Act, 1905. Powers and duties of distress committees and of the Central Body.
  - V.1-16. United Kingdom: Statutory Rules and Orders, 1905; 16 (Reel 1)
    No. 1071. Circular - Councils of populous boroughs and urban districts. Unemployed Workmen Act, 1905. Powers and duties of distress committees.
  - V.1-17. United Kingdom: Statutory Rules and Orders, 1905; 17 (Reel 1)
    No. 1071. Circular - Councils of Counties, and of County boroughs under 50,000 population. Unemployed Workmen Act, 1905.
  - V.1-18. United Kingdom: Statutory Rules and Orders, 1905; 18 (Reel 1)
    No. 1105. Unemployed workmen. Order of the Local Government Board ... October 21st ... amending Article IV of the Organisation (Unemployed Workmen) Establishment Oder, 1905
  - V.1-19. United Kingdom: Statutory Rules and Orders, 1905; 19 (Reel 1)
    No. 1195, Unemployed workmen. Order of the Local Government Board ... November 21 ... amending the Organisation (Unemployed Workmen) Establishment Order, 1905
  - V.1-20. United Kingdom: Statutory Rules and Orders, 1905; 20 (Reel 1)
    No. 1190. Unemployed Workmen. Order of the Local Government Board ... November 16 ... amending the Organisation (Unemployed Workmen) Establishment Order, 1905
  - V.1-21. United Kingdom: Statutory Rules and Orders, 1905; 21 (Reel 1)
    No. 1195. Unemployed Workmen. Order of the Local Government Board ... November 21 ... amending The Organisation (Unemployed Workmen) Establishment Order, 1905
  - V.1-22. United Kingdom: Statutory Rules and Orders, 1905; 22 (Reel 1)
    No. 1250. Unemployed Workmen. The Temporary Regulations (Organisation for Unemployed). 1905.
  - V.1-23. United Kingdom: Statutory Rules and Orders, 1906; 23 (Reel 1)
    No. 6. Unemployed Workmen. The Regulations (Organisation for Unemployed) 1906. (Record paper amendment).
  - V.1-24. United Kingdom: Statutory Rules and Orders, 1906; 24 (Reel 1)
    No. 7. Unemployed Workmen. The Temporary Regulations (Organisation for Unemployed), 1906.
  - V.1-25. United Kingdom: Statutory Rules and Orders, 1906; 25 (Reel 1)
    No. 454. Unemployed Workmen. Order of the Local Government Board, dated June 13, 1906, prescribing the form of the financial statement to be submitted to
  - V.1-26. United Kingdom: Statutory Rules and Orders, 1908; 26 (Reel 1)
    No. 942. Unemployed Workmen. The Regulations (Organisation for Unemployed) Second Series, 1908.
  - V.1-27. United Kingdom: Statutory Rules and Orders, 1908; 27 (Reel 1)
    No. 942. Circular - Distress Committees. Unemployed Workmen Act, 1905.
  - V.1-28. "The Times". Report of the Poor Law Commission., 1909; 28 (Reel 1)
  - V.1-29. BEmergency funds for the relief of the unemployed, 1906; 29 (Reel 1)
    Beveridge (Sir William Henry). Emergency funds for the relief of the unemployed. (In Clare Market Review: May 1906)
  - V.1-30. The Unemployed Workmen Act in 1906-7, 1908; 30 (Reel 1)
    Beveridge (Sir William Henry). The Unemployed Workmen Act in 1906-7. (Reprinted from Sociological Review, January. 1908)
  - V.1-31. Germany. Kaiserlichen Statistischen Amt., 31 (Reel 1)
    Die Regelung der Notstandsarbeiten in deutschen Stadten.
- Unemployment: Liverpool, etc., 1894-1908. V.3. Unemployment: Oxford, etc., 1897-1909.: V.2 (Reel 2)
  - V.2-1. Report of an inquiry into the condition of the unemployed, 1985-1986; 1 (Reel 2)
    Woodworth (Arthur V.). Report of an inquiry into the condition of the unemployed, conducted under the Toynbee Trust: Winter 1895-6.
  - V.2-2. Charity Organisation Society., 2 (Reel 2)
    Last year's unemployed: a summary of notes and reports.
  - V.2-3. The Enquirer's Club: 1., 1905; 3 (Reel 2)
    The Homeless Man, 1905
  - V.2-4. The Enquirer's Club: 2., 1905; 4 (Reel 2)
    The Boy in Industry: preliminary report, 1905.
  - V.2-5. Report of an inquiry into the conditions of dock labour at the Liverpool Docks, 1904; 5 (Reel 2)
    Rathbone (Eleanor F.). Report of an inquiry into the conditions of dock labour at the Liverpool Docks. 1904.
  - V.2-6. Unemployed in the City of Liverpool, 1894; 6 (Reel 2)
    Liverpool. Commission of Inquiry into the Subject of the Unemployed in the City of Liverpool, 1894. Full report.
  - V.2-7. An enquiry into the methods of obtaining employment in Liverpool, 1906-1907; 7 (Reel 2)
    D'Aeth (Frederic G.). An enquiry into the methods of obtaining employment in Liverpool. (In Transactions of the Liverpool Economic and Statistical Society. 1906-1907)
  - V.2-8. Unemployed (Workmen) Act, 1905, 1908; 8 (Reel 2)
    Stepney, Metropolitan Borough of: Unemployed (Workmen) Act, 1905. Report of the Stepney Distress Committee ... 1908.
  - V.2-9. The cotton crisis, 1904; 9 (Reel 2)
    Hutton (J. Arthur). The cotton crisis: paper read before the Economic Section of the British Association, Cambridge ... 1904.
  - V.2-10. Employment registries in Germany, 1907; 10 (Reel 2)
    Beveridge (Sir William Henry). Employment registries in Germany: address ... at Toynbee Hall ... 1907.
  - V.2-11. Unemployment in Germany, 11 (Reel 2)
    Barnes (George N.) and Henderson (Arthur): Unemployment in Germany: a report of an inquiry into the methods adopted in Germany for dealing with unemployment, presented to the Labour Party.
  - V.2-12. The Casual Ward System, 1894-1895; 12 (Reel 2)
    Pyddoke (H.W.): The Casual Ward System: abstract of an inquiry at the Whitechapel Union Casual Ward: ... 1894 ... 1895. (In the Toynbee Record April 1895)
  - V.2-13. Unemployment in London 1-3, 1904; 13 (Reel 2)
    Beveridge (Sir William Henry). Unemployment in London I. (In the Toynbee Record, October 1904). Beveridge (Sir William Henry) and Maynard (H.R.). Unemployment in London II: Mr. Long's proposals. Unemployment in London III: The making of paupers (In the Toynbee Record, November 1904)
  - V.2-15. Unemployment in London 4, 1904; 14 (Reel 2)
    Beveridge (Sir William Henry). Unemployment in London: IV, The preservation of efficiency. (In the Toynbee Record, December 1904)
  - V.2-16. The Casual Ward System 1, 1905; 15 (Reel 2)
    Thorp (H.). The Casual Ward System: I. Report of an inquiry in the Whitechapel Casual Ward during November and December 1905. (In the Toynbee Record, February 1905).
  - V.2-17. The Casual Ward System 2@ Unemployment in London 5, 1905; 16 (Reel 2)
    Thorp (H.). The Casual Ward System: II. Beveridge (Sir William Henry): Unemployment in London: V. The question of disfranchisement. (In the Toynbee Record. March 1905).
  - V.2-18. Metropolitan employment exchanges of the Central (Unemployed) Body, 1907; 17 (Reel 2)
    Beveridge (Sir William Henry): Metropolitan employment exchanges of the Central (Unemployed) Body. (In the Toynbee Record, July - September 1907)
  - V.2-19. Causes of unemployment, 1908; 18 (Reel 2)
    Harben (Henry D.). Causes of unemployment. (In the Toynbee Record, February 1908).
  - V.1-1Oxford and the Nation, 1907; 19 (Reel 2)
    The Times. Oxford and the Nation. (Reprint, 1907).
  - V.3-2. Oxford and Working-class education, 1908; 20 (Reel 2)
    Joint Committee of University and Working-class Representatives on the Relation of the University to the Higher Education of Workpeople: report, Oxford and Working-class education, 1908.
  - V.3-3. L'education des misereux a Londres, 1904; 21 (Reel 2)
    Guerard (Albert). L'education des misereux a Londres. (In "Le Volume", 17 September 1904.)
  - V.3-4. The Election of Guardians: by W.A.B., 22 (Reel 2)
  - V.3-5. Boy and Girl Labour, 1909; 23 (Reel 2)
    Adler (N.) and Tawney (R.H.): Boy and Girl Labour. 1909.
  - V.3-6. The poor law and the new Parliament, 24 (Reel 2)
    Mackay (T.). The poor law and the new Parliament.
  - V.3-7. Past experience in relief works, 1903; 25 (Reel 2)
    Bosanquet (Helen): Past experience in relief works. 1903.
  - V.3-8. Municipal Labour Bureaux, 1903; 26 (Reel 2)
    Charity Organisation Society, Council: April 20, 1903. Municipal Labour Bureaux.
  - V.3-9. London and the Unemployed problem, 27 (Reel 2)
    Charity Organisation Society: Occasional Paper. No. 5, fourth series. London and the Unemployed problem: by George C.T. Bartley.
  - V.3-10. he Unemployed: cause and cure, 1907; 28 (Reel 2)
    Sharpe (Henry). The Unemployed: cause and cure: 1907.
  - V.3-11. Unemployment, 29 (Reel 2)
    Christian Social Union: Oxford University Branch.. Leaflet No. 45. Unemployment.
  - V.3-12. The new unemployed bill of the Labour Party, 30 (Reel 2)
    MacDonald (James Ramsay). The new unemployed bill of the Labour Party.
  - V.3-13. The Unemployed Workmen Bill of the Labour Party, 1908; 31 (Reel 2)
    Jones (J.H.). The Unemployed Workmen Bill of the Labour Party. 1908.
  - V.3-14. The Unemployed, 32 (Reel 2)
    Social-Democratic Federation.. The Unemployed.
  - V.3-15. The right to work, 33 (Reel 2)
    The Right to Work National Council.. The right to work: a common-sense team. the idle man and the idle land: a proposal for the unemployed.
  - V.3-16. John Bull and his unemployed, 1905; 34 (Reel 2)
    Hardie (J. Keir). John Bull and his unemployed: a plain statement on the law of England as it affects the unemployed. 1905.
  - V.3-17. The unemployed problem, with some suggestions for solving it, 1904; 35 (Reel 2)
    Hardie (J. Keir). The unemployed problem, with some suggestions for solving it. 1904.
  - V.3-18. A reproach to civilization, 1906; 36 (Reel 2)
    Hatch (E.F.G.). A reproach to civilization: a treatise on the problem of the unemployed and some suggestions for a possible solution. 1906.
  - V.3-19. Unemployment, a problem of industry, 37 (Reel 2)
    Beveridge (Sir William Henry). Unemployment, a problem of industry (preface and contents).
  - V.3-20. Labour colonies: what are they? What can they do?, 38 (Reel 2)
    Hunt (William H.). Labour colonies: what are they? What can they do?
  - V.3-21. The Unemployed: Hollesley Bay farm colony experiment, 1907; 39 (Reel 2)
    Gunning (James). The Unemployed: Hollesley Bay farm colony experiment. (Reprinted from the Amalgamated Engineers' Monthly Journal. March-May, 1907).
  - V.3-22. The Poplar Labour Colony at Dunton, near Laindon, 1904; 40 (Reel 2)
    Poplar Board of Guardians.. The Poplar Labour Colony at Dunton, near Laindon, Essex. 1904.
  - V.3-23. The Unemployable and the unemployed, 1904; 41 (Reel 2)
    Paton (J.B.). The Unemployable and the unemployed. 1904.
  - V.3-24. the tramp ward: social investigation, 1904; 42 (Reel 2)
    Higgs (Mary). the tramp ward: social investigation. (Reprinted from the Contemporary Review, May, 1904).
  - V.3-25. Die deutschen Arbeiter-Kolonien, 1897; 43 (Reel 2)
    Berthold (G.). Die deutschen Arbeiter-Kolonien, ihre Entstehung und Entwicklung 1882 bis 1895 nebst Individualstatistik fur 1891-93. VII. Folge. Auf Grund der offiziellen Zahlkarten. 1897.
  - V.3-26. Industrial invalids, 1904; 44 (Reel 2)
    Christian Social Union. Oxford University Branch.. Industrial invalids. I. The unemployed and unemployable: by ... Samuel A. Barnett. II. The Belgian labour colonies by H.J. Torr. 1904.
  - V.3-27. Summary of information respecting casuals, 1904; 45 (Reel 2)
    Barnett (James). Summary of information respecting casuals: collected and tabulated by the master of the [King's Lynn Union] Workhouse during September 1904.
  - V.3-28. The recurring problem of the unemployed, 1905; 46 (Reel 2)
    Booth (William):. The recurring problem of the unemployed. One permanent remedy: emigration-colonisation: proposals for the better distribution of the people ... with a report of the work of the Emigration Office of the Salvation Army. 1905.
- Unemployment, etc., 1890-1914. V.4. (Reel 3)
  - V.4-1. The causes of unemployment, 1909; 1 (Reel 3)
    Jevons (H. Stanley): The causes of unemployment. (Extracted from the Contemporary Review for May, July and August, 1909).
  - V.4-2. A "fixed value of bullion" standard, 1892; 2 (Reel 3)
    Williams (Aneurin): A "fixed value of bullion" standard. (Reprinted, with additions, from the Economic Journal, June 1892).
  - V.4-3. Address to the British Association for the Advancement of Science, 1910; 3 (Reel 3)
    Smith (Sir H. Llewellyn): Address to the Economic science and Statistics Section of the British Association for the Advancement of Science. 1910.
  - V.4-4. Some lessons of his life, 1913; 4 (Reel 3)
    Ebor (Cosmo): Samuel Augustus Barnett: Some lessons of his life. (Toynbee Record, November 1913).
  - V.4-5. Casual labour at the docks, 1889 and 1914, 5 (Reel 3)
    Mess (H.A.): Casual labour at the docks, 1889 and 1914. (Mansfield House Magazine, September 1914)
  - V.4-6. Casual labour at the docks: I and II, 1912; 6 (Reel 3)
    Langdon (W.M.): Casual labour at the docks: I and II. (The Toynbee Record, February and March 1912).
  - V.4-7. The dock-strike, 1912; 7 (Reel 3)
    Carr-Saunders (A.M.): The dock-strike: (The Toynbee Record, July-September 1912).
  - V.4-8. Causes of unemployment, 1908; 8 (Reel 3)
    Harben (Henry D.): Causes of unemployment. (The Toynbee Record, February 1908).
  - V.4-9. Unemployment: a symposium of platitudes, 9 (Reel 3)
    Toynbee Record, November 1908. Unemployment: a symposium of platitudes.
  - V.4-10. Hollesley Bay, 1908; 10 (Reel 3)
    Sturge (H.E.): Hollesley Bay. (The Toynbee Record, March 1908).
  - V.4-11. An inquiry into the state feeding of school children, 1909; 11 (Reel 3)
    Tallents (S.G.): An inquiry into the state feeding of school children (Toynbee Record, March 1909).
  - V.4-12. Boy labour and unemployment, 1909; 12 (Reel 3)
    Lesser (Ernest): Boy labour and unemployment. (Toynbee Record, March 1909).
  - V.4-13. Committee on Wage-earning Children, 1900; 13 (Reel 3)
    Committee on Wage-earning Children: report, 1900.
  - V.4-14. Unemployment of Women Dependent on their own Earnings, 1907; 14 (Reel 3)
    National Conference on the Unemployment of Women Dependent on their own Earnings: report, 1907.
  - V.4-15. Salvation Army Sweating, 1908; 15 (Reel 3)
    United Workers' Anti-Sweating Committee: manifesto: Salvation Army Sweating. 1908.
  - V.4-16. Employment exchanges, 1907; 16 (Reel 3)
    Beveridge (Sir William Henry): Employment exchanges. 1907.
  - V.4-17. Labour exchanges, 1907; 17 (Reel 3)
    Beveridge (Sir William Henry): Labour exchanges. 1907.
  - V.4-18. Report on proposed purchase of land for reclamation and improvement, 1907; 18 (Reel 3)
    Edinburgh Distress Committee. Land Purchase Sub-Committee. Report on proposed purchase of land for reclamation and improvement. 1907.
  - V.4-18A. The Government and Unemployment, 1909; 19 (Reel 3)
    Layton (Walter T.): The Government and Unemployment. (Saint George, July 1909).
  - V.4-19. The Minority Report: a criticism, 1910; 20 (Reel 3)
  - V.4-20. The decline in the birth rate, 1907; 21 (Reel 3)
    Webb (Sidney): The decline in the birth rate. (Fabian Tract. No. 131). 1907.
  - V.4-21. Notes on money and international exchanges, 1899; 22 (Reel 3)
    Phear (Sir John B.): Notes on money and international exchanges. 1899.
  - V.4-22. Note on a Court roll of Hulham Manor, 1890; 23 (Reel 3)
    Phear (Sir John B.): Note on a Court roll of Hulham Manor. (Reprinted from the Transactions of the Devonshire Association for the Advancement of Science, Literature and Art, 1890).
  - V.4-23. Recent repairs to the Castle at Exeter, 1895; 24 (Reel 3)
    Phear (Sir John B.): Recent repairs to the Castle at Exeter. (Reprinted from the Transactions of the Devonshire Association for the Advancement of Science, Literature and Art. 1895).
  - V.4-25. The Hide examined, 1904; 25 (Reel 3)
    Phear (Sir John B.): The Hide examined. (Reprinted from the Transactions of the Devonshire Association for the Advancement of Science, Literature and Art. 1904).
  - V.4-26. Molland accounts, 1903; 26 (Reel 3)
    Phear (Sir John B.): Molland accounts: with an introductory note on the evolution of parishes. (Reprinted from the Transactions of the Devonshire Association for the Advancement of Science, Literature and Art. 1903).
  - V.4-26A. On the Association's English version of the Devonshire Domesday, 1893; 27 (Reel 3)
    Phear (Sir John B.): On the Association's English version of the Devonshire Domesday. (Reprinted from the Transactions of the Devonshire Association for the Advancement of Science, Literature and Art. 1893).
  - V.4-27. Agenda of a meeting of the Council, 1907; 28 (Reel 3)
    Lambeth, Metropolitan Borough of: Agenda of a meeting of the Council to be held 14 February 1907.
  - V.4-28. New series, No. 11, 1909; 29 (Reel 3)
    United Kingdom. Reports to the Local Government Board on Public Health and Medical Subjects. New series, No. 11. Dr. Reginald Farrar's report ... on the conditions under which persons are employed in pea-picking, with ... observations on the employment of casual labour in agricultural districts, and an appendix giving the police regulations in force during the hop-picking season in certain districts of Bavaria. 1909.
  - V.4-29. New series, No. 14, 1909; 30 (Reel 3)
    United Kingdom. Reports to the Local Government Board on Public Health and Medical Subjects. New series, No. 14. Dr. Reginald Farrar's Report ... on the lodging of workmen employed in the construction of public works. 1909.
  - V.4-30. the training of volunteers, 1895; 31 (Reel 3)
    Gardner (Mrs. Dunn): the training of volunteers. (Charities Review, February 1895).
  - V.4-31. Bevolkerungsbewegung, Kapitalbildung und periodische Wirtschaftskrisen, 1902; 32 (Reel 3)
    Pohle (Ludwig): Bevolkerungsbewegung, Kapitalbildung und periodische Wirtschaftskrisen. 1902.
  - V.4-32. Correspondenzblatt, 1907; 33 (Reel 3)
    Generalkommission der Gewerkschaften Deutschlands, Correspondenzblatt, 17th August 1907.
  - V.4-33. Puss in Boots: a Christmas play, 1907; 34 (Reel 3)
    Darton (F.J. Harvey): Puss in Boots: a Christmas play. 1907.
  - V.4-34. In Memoriam Canon Barnett, 1903; 35 (Reel 3)
    In Memoriam Canon Barnett: by F.J.H.D. (The Toynbee Record, July-September 1903).
  - V.4-35. Extract headed "Experience", 1908; 36 (Reel 3)
    London: Central (Unemployed) Body for London ... Extract headed "Experience" from second report of Central Body ... 1907, with explanatory comments of Chairman. 1908.
  - V.4-36. Report of the proceedings. Vagrancy, 1905; 37 (Reel 3)
    Conference of Representatives of Lancashire, Cheshire, Westmoreland and Cumberland Unions. Report of the proceedings. Vagrancy. 1905.
  - V.4-37. Les sans -travail a Londres, 38 (Reel 3)
    "Musee Social". February 1904. Les sans -travail a Londres.
  - V.4-38. The Vagrant and the "unemployable", 1904; 39 (Reel 3)
    Booth (William): The Vagrant and the "unemployable": a proposal for the extension of the land and industrial colony system, whereby vagrants may be detained under suitable conditions and compelled to work: ... with a report and notes by Col. David C. Lamb, ... and contributions ... by Mr. Bramwell Booth and others. 1904.
  - V.4-39. Summary of information respecting casuals, 1904; 40 (Reel 3)
  - V.4-40. The problem of the unemployed, 1905; 41 (Reel 3)
    Toynbee (H.V.): The problem of the unemployed. (The Economic Review, July 1905).
  - V.4-41. Les premiers resultats de la nouvelle loi anglaise d'assurance sociale, 1903; 42 (Reel 3)